Stefano SPIGLER, Ph.D.

Resume

BIRTHPLACE
BIRTHDATE
PHONE NUMBER
EMAIL
WEBSITE
CONTACT ADDRESS

Padova, ITALY
March 16, 1990
+41 (0) 787 424 858
stefano@spigler.net
spigler.net/stefano
Rue du centre 50
CH-1025 St-Sulpice VD
Switzerland



KEY STRENGTHS

- I consider myself a versatile person able to adapt to novel situations and to learn new concepts and acquire new skills in a short time. Indeed: I have lived in several countries (learning new languages) and I have been enjoying the challenge of building a life abroad; I can show a track of high-level scientific publications in two different research fields (statistical physics and machine learning).
- I strongly believe that a well-organized synergy is a great way to unlock the full potential of each individual. I am a team player and I am used to interactions with superiors and subordinates.
- My studies and my research prove that I have strong analytical and communication skills. I am
 used to modeling complex data and extracting information out of it. I have a broad experience in
 computer programming, data analysis and machine learning. I am proficient in several languages,
 and I can summarize and explain complex results in an easy-to-understand fashion.

Work Experience

2017–2020 Postdoc in Deep Learning at EPFL

- During my stay at EPFL I conducted research on deep learning, both studying analytical models and performing numerical simulations.
- Brief summary of the main contributions: 1) The performance of deep neural networks increases with the number of parameters (there is no overfitting). However, averaging the prediction of two large networks is much better than training a network twice as big. 2) Kernel methods can be used efficiently on high-dimensional data, provided that the task depends effectively on a reduced number of variables.
- Besides research duties, the position involved teaching activities at the EPFL, the supervision of master students and public speaking at numerous international venues.

2014–2017 Ph.D. in Physics at Université Paris Sud

- The research that I carried out for my Ph.D. revolved around the statistical physics of disordered systems, namely granular material and structural glasses.
- When subject to external perturbations, these systems tumble in avalanches, that are characterized by a critical exponent. My main result consisted in deriving this exponent both analytically and via numerical simulations.

EDUCATION

2012–2014 M.Sc. in Physics of Complex Systems. Joint programme involving: Politecnico di Torino, SISSA, ICTP; Université Pierre et Marie Curie, Université Paris Diderot, Université Paris Sud, ENS de Cachan.

Ranked 1st among the whole class.

Final grade 110/110 cum laude.

2009–2012 Italian *Laurea* (**B.Sc.**) in **Physics**, Università degli Studi di Padova, Padua.

Final grade 107/110.

2009–2012 Scuola Galileiana di Studi Superiori of Padova, Padua.

This college is affiliated with the University of Padova; students are required to pass all the exams each year with grade above 24/30 and average GPA above 27/30; attendance to additional courses is also required.

Honors & Awards

2013 Scholarship awarded by the **Université Paris Sud**.

2009–2012 Full merit scholarship awarded by **Scuola Galileiana di Studi Superiori**.

Ranked 4th among over 600 candidates

Award for the results obtained in the National Mathematical Olympiad.

Informatics & Programming

• I know a variety of languages and I feel at ease with new challenges.

- ullet I program in Python, especially to design and train neural networks with Pytorch, a popular framework for machine learning. $-4~\mathrm{YEARS}$
- I perform data analysis using the popular libraries Pandas, NumPy, SciPy. 4 YEARS
- Data visualization with the business intelligence application Apache Superset. − 1 YEAR
- I have designed several websites using HTML, XML, CSS, PHP (personal projects only). I have basic knowledge of JavaScript (AJAX) and SQL. 15 YEARS
- ullet I have developed complex programs in C++, including all the code I wrote during my PhD. 10 YEARS
- \bullet During my researched I have published several articles, all redacted in LaTeX. I am also accustomed to the Office suite (Word, Excel). $-10~{
 m YEARS}$
- \bullet I have experience working with Ubuntu and Windows operating systems. 15 YEARS

LANGUAGES & COMMUNICATION

Italian (native language)

American **English** (full command)

French (fluent)

German (beginner)

• I write proficiently in Italian, English and French. In English, I have published numerous scientific articles in peer-reviewed journals and I have presented my work at international conferences.

OTHER PERSONAL INFORMATION

Swiss B permit A and B driving licences Italian citizenship